smaato.net 2015-05-08

# Privacy Policy

Smaato, Inc., (“ **Smaato** “, “ **we** “, or “ **our** “) values the privacy of our users, members, and others who visit and use [www.smaato.com](http://www.smaato.com/) (the “Smaato Site”) (collectively or individually “ **Users** ” or “ **you** “). The Smaato Site may contain information regarding a variety of services offered by Smaato (collectively the “ **Service** “). This statement (“ **Privacy Policy** “) governs information you provide to us or that we learn from your use of the Smaato Site and tells you how we may collect, use, and in some instances share this information.

**User Provided Information:** – When registering an account or expressing an interest in obtaining additional information about Smaato or the Service you may provide to Smaato what is generally called “personally identifiable” information such as your name, postal mailing address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit card number, and other billing information. In addition, Smaato may give you the option to provide us with certain information about your business.

**“Cookies” Information:** – When you visit the Smaato Site, we may send one or more cookies – a small text file containing a string of alphanumeric characters – to your computer. Smaato may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Smaato Site. By using these cookies, we can “remember” what you have done on the Smaato Site before and personalize our site for you. These persistent types of cookies can be removed. Each web browser implements different functionality, so please refer to the manuals or technical support resources that are available in conjunction with your web browser to learn the correct way to modify your cookies set-up. Please note that disabling cookies, if any, may prevent you from accessing some of the functionality and offerings available via the Smaato Site.

**“Automatically Collected” Information:** – When you visit the Smaato Site or open one of our HTML emails, we may record certain information from your web browser by using different types of technology, including “clear gifs” or “web beacons”. This “automatically collected” information may include your Internet Protocol address (“IP Address”), web browser type, the web pages or sites that you visit just before or just after the Smaato Site, the pages you view on our site, and the dates and times that you visit. When your end users connect to the Service on their mobile device, Smaato may automatically receive from their mobile phone service provider information identifying their unique mobile device, their phone number and/or other unique identifiers for their device (“Mobile Device Information”). For the avoidance of doubt, your end users are not “Users” covered by this Privacy Policy, and any information that you collect from your end users is governed by your privacy policy, if any, and not this Privacy Policy.

**“Retargeting”** – Smaato uses retargeting technologies in the internet. This enables to reach those internet users with advertising who were already interested in our services. The retargeting advertisements are shown on cookie based analysis of user behavior. Naturally there will be no personal data be saved and the usage of retargeting technology is effected under consideration of effective legal privacy policies.

Smaato uses the information that we collect to provide the Service and all of the features and services found on the Smaato Site, to consistently improve Smaato’s services and products, including the Service, to fulfill your requests regarding Smaato and/or the Service, and to contact you about special offers and new products and services. We will also use your email address, without further consent, for non-marketing or administrative purposes such as notifying you of major site updates.

Smaato may use all of the information that we collect from our Users to understand the usage trends and preferences, to improve the way the Smaato Site works and looks, to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, and to create new features and functionality.

Smaato may use automatically collected information and cookies information to: (a) remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Smaato Site; (b) provide custom, personalized advertisements, content, and information; (c) monitor the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns; and (d) monitor aggregate usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed.

Smaato may disclose both personally identifiable and automatically collected information to affiliated companies or other businesses or persons to process such information on our behalf, to provide website maintenance and security, to offer certain features on the Service and the Smaato Site, to assist us in improving the way the Service and the Smaato Site work and look, and to create new features. We use reasonable efforts to: (i) see that these parties process such information in compliance with our Privacy Policy, (ii) limit their use of such information, and (iii) see that these parties use other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

We may share automatically collected and other aggregate non-personally-identifiable information with interested third parties to assist them in understanding the usage patterns for certain content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on the Service and the Smaato Site.

Except as otherwise noted in this Privacy Policy, Smaato does not share personal information about Users with third parties unless doing so is appropriate to carry out a User’s request or it reasonably believes that doing so is legally required or is in Smaato’s interest to protect its property or other legal rights or the rights or property of others.

We do not share your personally identifiable information with other third-party organizations for their marketing or promotional use without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in.

You have access to your personal information and you may update, correct, or delete your member information and email preferences at any time by logging-in to your account and changing the information on file or by e-mailing Smaato at support(at)smaato(dot)com with your request. To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting Users profile access. YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR MAINTAINING THE SECRECY OF YOUR UNIQUE PASSWORD AND ACCOUNT INFORMATION AT ALL TIMES.

Consistent with the federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of thirteen (13) without requiring parental consent (hereafter “Children Information”). If we will become aware that Smaato has collected or received such Children Information without requesting or receiving prior parent consent, we will use reasonable efforts to remove such information from Smaato’s records.

Smaato may allow other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within the Smaato Site. These third-party ad servers or ad networks may use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear within the Smaato Site. They may automatically receive your IP Address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize their advertising content.

Smaato does not provide any of your personally identifiable information to these third-party ad servers or ad networks without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you will have the ability to opt-in. However, please note that if an advertiser asks Smaato to show an advertisement to a certain audience or audience segment and you respond to that advertisement, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they were trying to reach.

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers or ad networks. Smaato’s Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites.

No data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make reasonable efforts to ensure security on our systems. We use secure server software (SSL) and firewalls to protect your information from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, please note that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of such firewalls and secure server software. You can help to ensure the security of your information by taking simple precautions such as preventing unauthorized access to your log-in information and signing-off of your account when you are finished using your computer.

If Smaato learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using the Smaato Site or providing personal information to us, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of the Smaato Site. Smaato may post a notice on the Smaato Site if a security breach occurs. If this happens, you will need a web browser enabling you to view Smaato’s Service. Smaato may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive a free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us via email at privacy(at)smaato(dot)com.

If Smaato should ever file for bankruptcy or have its assets or stock sold to or merge with another entity, information Smaato receives from you through the Smaato Site is a Smaato asset and may be transferred to any such entity.

We may occasionally update this Privacy Policy. When we do, we will also revise the “Last Updated” section below. For changes to this Privacy Policy that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of your personal information going forward, we will notify you via the most recent email address that we have on file, if any, and we will attempt to obtain your consent before implementing the change. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay informed about how we are protecting the personal information we collect. Your continued use of the Smaato Site constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any updates.

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please email us at privacy(a)smaato(dot)com, or call us at +1 (650) 286-1198 (AMERICAS), +49 (0)40 3480 9490 (EMEA) and +65 3157 1444 (APAC).

#### Sign up to use Smaato’s global platform to access advertising inventory in all countries

### NEWSLETTER

Sign Up for the Publisher Newsletter

### INTERNATIONAL OFFICES

SPX

The Smaato Publisher Platform

Smaato

Legacy Smaato Portal

Accounts created before January 15, 2015
